Guide to the John Betjeman Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1936-1983; Series II; 4.0 linear feet (4 boxes)
  Themes explored in Betjeman's poetry, such as religion and architecture, also pervade his essays and media work. For example, among Betjeman's essays and articles are his The City of London Churches and series on London neighbourhoods "Ballet-Goer's London Guide" published with illustrations by David Thomas in Ballet.
  Broadcast scripts concern Betjeman's work in radio and television, the recordings for which can be found in the Audiovisual Series. The scripts include Betjeman's own series, such as BBC's "Buildings and Places" and "Three in Hand," in addition to programs on which Betjeman was interviewed or which included his poetry.
  The Reviews subseries contains Betjeman's reviews of other authors for various magazines. Betjeman's Other Writings vary from his farcical magazine "The DOOGG Weekly," written for Penelope Chetwode, to a translation and various introductions. The subseries Writings of Others include derivatives of Betjeman's work and biographies and criticism of the author.
  - Major Works
    - Church Poems
      - Galley proofs, corrected, 1978 February 8
      - Author's proofs, revised printing, 1980 June 5 (Box 2, Folder 107)
      - Page proofs, revised printing, 1980 December 31 (Box 2, Folder 108)
      - Paste-ups, 1980
      - Printed version, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 109-110)
    - Continual Dew
      - "Suicide After Abstention From Evening Communion in North London," "Muscular Christianity," "A Commercial Traveler," "A Hike With a First or Wykehamist Redivivus," and "Dorset," drafts, holograph and typescript, signed, corrected, Before 1937 (Box 2, Folder 111)
      - Designer's layout, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 112)
        Includes type instructions to the printer and misspelling of Betjeman as "Bateman" on titlepage
    - Ground Plan to Skyline
      - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 113)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 114)
      - Setting copy, typescript, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 115)
      - Galley proof, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 116)
      - Printed versions, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - High and Low
      - Galley proof, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - John Betjeman's Collected Poems
      - Printed version, second printing, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 119-120)
        Copy belonged to Roger Senhouse and includes his notes as well as loose material such as correspondence, notes, and clippings
    - Lord Mount Prospect
      - Proof copy, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 121-122)
    - Mount Zion
      - Galley proof, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - New Bats in Old Belfries
      - Setting copy, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 124-125)
      - Page proofs, corrected, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 126-127)
    - A Nip in the Air
      - Page proofs, bound, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 128)
    - Old Lights for New Chancels
      - Page proofs, bound, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 129)
    - Summoned by Bells
      - Drafts, holograph, corrected, Before 1960 (Box 3, Folder 130)
      - Page proofs, corrected, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 131)
        Includes early dust wrapper
      - Publicity, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 132)
      - Excerpted printed version, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Uncollected Poems
      - Galley proofs, 1982
      - Page proofs, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 134-135)
  - Single Poems
    Untitled poems are listed here by first line (as indicated by the absence of quotation marks)
    - "1930 Commercial Style," draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - "And Is It True?"
      - Printed version, included in Assembly Workshop compiled by Ronald Dingwall, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 137-139)
        London: Darton, Longman, and Todd
      - Musical score set to Betjeman's poem by Mervyn Horder, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - "Anglo-Catholic Congress," draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - "An Archaeological Picnic," draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - "The Arrest of Oscar Wilde in the Cadogan Hotel," holograph, undated (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - "Autumn 1964," holograph, undated (Box 3, Folder 144)
      Copied out for Marshall Bean
    - The Barrier: A Novel Containing Five Sonnets by John Betjeman by Robin Maugham, drafts, holograph, corrected, signed and first draft, typescript, circa 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 145-146)
    - "A Bay in Anglesey," holograph, illustrated, signed, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - "Before Invasion 1940," draft, holograph, corrected (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - "Before the Anaesthetic, or, A Real Fright," draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - "Big Business," drafts, holograph, signed, undated (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - "The Brent, Perivale," printed version, In and Out, 1954 May (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - "Bristol," draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - "Cheltenham," drafts, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - "Cheshire Lines," drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - "Civilised Woman," holograph and typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - "Clay and Spirit," typescript, signed, undated (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - "Cornish Cliffs," draft, holograph, signed, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 157)
    - "Christmas," printed version, Poetry Society, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 158)
    - "Delectable Duchy," draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - "East Anglian Bathe," drafts, holograph and typescript, illustrated; printed version, Argosy, undated, 1962 August (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - "Eighteenth-Century Print," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 161)
    - The Essex Fields Try to Push Their Verdure Through, holograph, signed, undated (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - From Hampstead Garden Suburb, draft, holograph, undated (Box 3, Folder 163)
    - "George V," holograph, undated (Box 3, Folder 164)
    - Goo-bell! Goobell! On this hillock, draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 165)
    - "Great Central Railway," drafts, holograph, corrected, 1962, undated (Box 3, Folder 166)
    - "Great Life: Letchworth," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 167)
    - "Harrow-on-the-Hill," draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 168)
    - "Henley-on-Thames," drafts, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 169)
    - Here on the sooty London height, draft, holograph, undated (Box 3, Folder 170)
    - "How to Get on In Society," printed version, undated (Box 3, Folder 171)
    - "An Impoverished Irish Peer," draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 172)
    - I like to put until it falls, draft fragment, holograph, undated (Box 3, Folder 173)
    - "In Holy Trinity, Sloane Street," typescripts and printed version, Yellow Jacket, 1939 March (Box 3, Folder 174)
    - "In Westminster Abbey," typescript carbon, undated (Box 3, Folder 175)
    - "Indoor Games Near Newbury," draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 176)
    - "Ireland With Emily," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 177)
    - "A Lament for Moira McCavendish," drafts, holograph, corrected and printed versions, undated (Box 3, Folder 178)
    - "Lines Written to Martyn Skinner Before His Departure From Oxfordshire in Search of Quiet," draft, holograph, corrected and printed version S. Cuthbert with S. Matthias, Earls Court, 1964 Spring (Box 3, Folder 179)
    - "Margate," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 180)
    - "May-Day Song for North Oxford," drafts, holograph, corrected and printed version, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 181)
    - "Meditation on a Lucas Mezzotint of a Constable Picture," printed version Do You Care About Historic Buildings?: The Work of This Historic Buildings Board of the Great London Council, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 182)
    - My four footed friends, they bark all night, holograph, illustrated, undated (Box 3, Folder 183)
    - "Narcissus," galley proof for London Magazine, circa 1958
    - "The Newest Bath Guide by the New Christopher Anstey," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 184)
    - "Old Friends," typescript, signed, 1962 April (Box 3, Folder 185)
    - "The Old Liberals," printed version, Horizon, 1949 April (Box 3, Folder 186)
    - "Olney Hymns," typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 3, Folder 187)
    - "On Hearing the Full Peal of Ten Bells From Christ Church, Swindon, Wilts," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 188)
    - "On Miss. E. Badger," holograph, corrected, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 189)
    - "On Leaving Wantage," holograph, corrected, signed, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 190)
    - "On Seeing an Old Poet in the Café Royal," typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 3, Folder 191)
    - "Parliament Hill Fields," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 192)
    - Pew openers, beadles, charity children, draft, holograph, signed, undated (Box 3, Folder 193)
    - "A Poem By My Old Bear Archibald," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 194)
    - "Pot Pourri From a Surrey Garden," draft, holograph, undated (Box 3, Folder 195)
    - "The Planster's Vision," page proof, New English Review, and printed version, Rhyme and Reason, 1945, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 196)
    - "Quaker Silence," draft, holograph, undated (Box 3, Folder 197)
    - "Revenge," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 198)
    - "Saint Cadoc," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 199)
    - "Saint Saviour's, Aberdeen Park, Highbury, London N.," draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 200)
    - "Shetland 1973," draft, holograph and typescript, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 201)
    - "A Shropshire Lad," typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 202)
    - "Slides," draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 203)
    - "Slough," draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 204)
    - "The Small Towns of Ireland," draft, holograph, undated (Box 3, Folder 205)
    - "South London Sketch, 1844," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 206)
    - "South London Sketch, 1944," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 207)
    - "Station Syren," printed version, Argosy, 1956 February (Box 3, Folder 208)
    - "A Subaltern's Love Song," draft, holograph, corrected and printed version, Argosy, undated, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 209)
    - "Summer Poem," printed version, The Wind and the Rain, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 210)
    - So devises on a winter Saturday night, draft fragment, holograph, undated (Box 3, Folder 211)
    - "Sunday Morning, King's Cambridge," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1947-1964 (Box 3, Folder 212)
      Includes letter from Betjeman regarding interpretation of poem (1964 September 28)
    - "Tea With Poets," holograph, undated (Box 3, Folder 213)
    - "Telford," acrostic poem, draft, holograph,corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 214)
    - Thus Sidmouth looked an hundred years ago," holograph, undated (Box 3, Folder 215)
    - "Trebetherick," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 216)
    - "Tregardock," page proof, corrected, signed, undated (Box 3, Folder 217)
    - "To Uffington Ringers," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 218)
    - Undenominational, holograph, undated (Box 3, Folder 219)
    - "Verses Turned In Aid of a Public Subscription Towards the Restoration of the Church of St. Katherine, Chiselhampton, Oxon.," printed versions, undated (Box 3, Folder 220)
    - "Winter Seascape," draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 221)
    - Yes, the guv'nors still living in Streatham, draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 222)
    - Various poems, 1967, undated (Box 3, Folder 223)
      Includes poems signed by Betjeman as well as letter from Betjeman stating that he never signs poems he hasn't typed himself (1967 October 10). Poems include: "Olney Hymns," "In a Bath Teashop," "Daily Express," and "Inevitable."
    - Untitled draft fragment, undated (Box 3, Folder 224)
      Written on the back of a letter from Terence Greenidge (1945 July 8)
  - Essays and Articles
    - "Architecture," printed version, signed, Studies in the History of Swindon, undated (Box 3, Folder 225)
    - "Ballet-Goer's London Guide," drafts, holograph, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 226-228)
      Includes articles "Charing Cross Road" (no. 3, February), "Ivy House (4, March), "Hanover Square" (5, April), and "Pheasantry" (no. 7, June) accompanied by pen and ink drawing by David Thomas
    - The City of London Churches, printed version, signed, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 229)
      London: Garrod and Lofthouse, 1972
    - "Clifton College Buildings," reprinted from Centenary Essays on Clifton College, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 230)
    - "Diary of Percy Progress," copies of printed version, Night and Day, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 231)
    - "Henry Kendall," printed version, Diary of Events, Lincolnshire Association, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 232)
    - "Norfolk Churches," drafts, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 3, Folder 233)
    - "Old Books," draft, typescript, corrected and printed versions, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 234)
      Written for the Book Collectors Fair 1966
    - Oscar Wilde: A Memoir by Theodore Wratislaw, foreward, proofs, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 235)
    - "Oxford," printed version, Programme, 1936 March 11 (Box 3, Folder 236)
      Number 15
    - "A Plea for Holy Trinity Church, Sloane Street," printed version, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 237)
      With drawings by Gavin Stamp
    - "Parson Hawker, Cornish Mystic," printed version, Orthodox Observer, 1974 Autumn (Box 3, Folder 238)
      Number 56
    - "Pleasures and Palaces," printed version, Diversions: Twenty-Two Authors on the Lively Arts, edited by John Sutro, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 239)
      London: Max Parrish
    - "A Shell Guide to Typography," printed version, photocopied excerpt, Typography, 1937 Spring (Box 3, Folder 240)
    - "West Country Churches: Four Essays," printed version, signed, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 241)
    - Untitled article on Barrie Humphries, printed version, undated (Box 3, Folder 242)
  - Broadcast Scripts
    - "Buildings and Places: Padstow," typescript, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 243)
      Buildings and Places No. 8
    - "Café Royal: A Study in Conversation and Reminiscence," photocopies of typescript, 1955, 1962-1968 (Box 3, Folder 244)
    - "Hugh Gaitskill: A Radio Portrait," typescript, corrected, 1964 January (Box 3, Folder 245)
      Compiled by Kenneth Harris and Robert Pocock with Betjeman's recollections of Hugh Gaitskill
    - "In Defence of the Beard," typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, 1949 January 29 (Box 3, Folder 246)
      Pamphlet by James Ward read by Lockwood West
    - "I Remember," typescript, corrected, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 247)
    - "John Betjeman at 70 by John Sparrow," typescript, copy, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 248)
    - "The Masters: T.S. Eliot Remembered by John Betjeman," excerpt, typescript, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 249)
    - "New Comment," photocopy of typescript and typescript, corrected, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 250)
      Anthony Thwaite interviews John Betjeman about Summoned by Bells
    - "Personal Choice," typescript, corrected, 1958 February (Box 4, Folder 251)
      Chosen and introduced by John Betjeman and read by John Betjeman and Cecil Day Lewis
    - "Poetry Programme" by Robert Donat, typescript, copy, 1953, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 252)
      Programme included Betjeman's poem "Death in Leamington"
    - "Portrait of Martin Willson," typescript, 1962 March (Box 4, Folder 253)
      Tribute by Frank Gillard with contribution by John Betjeman
    - "Pride of Place" press release and reviews, typescript, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 254)
    - "Scenes That Are Brightest," typescript, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 255)
    - "Tennyson as a Humourist," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 256)
    - "Three in Hand: Three Churches," draft, typescript, 1948 August (Box 4, Folder 257)
    - "Trains of Thought," draft, typescript, corrected, 1953 May (Box 4, Folder 258)
    - "Victorian Knights," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 259)
      Introduction by Betjeman
    - "We Beg to Differ," typescript, corrected, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 260)
      Panel on which Betjeman participated
  - Reviews
    - "The Diary of a Somebody," Review of Recollections of Thomas Graham Jackson ed. by Basil H. Jackson, draft, holograph, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 261)
    - "The Land of Railways," Review of British Railway History: An Outline from the Accession of William IV to the Nationalization of Railways, 1827-1947 by Hamilton Ellis, draft fragment, holograph, corrected, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 262)
    - "Neckwear," Review of School, University, Navy, Army, Air-Force, and Club Ties, draft, typescript, corrected, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 263)
    - "Prolific Scott," Review of Mr. Loudon's England by John Gloag, draft, holograph, corrected, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 264)
    - "The Public Gallery of the Streets," Reviews of Looking at Townscape by Christopher Hussey and Oxford Observed by Thomas Sharpe, draft, holograph, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 265)
  - Other Writings
    - "The DOOGG Weekly" and questionnaire, holograph, illustrated, circa 1933 (Box 4, Folder 266)
    - Exhibition catalogues, 1951-1981 (Box 4, Folder 267-271)
    - "Foreward." Rose, Clarkson, Red Plush and Greasepaint: A Memory of Music-Halls from the Nineties to the Sixties, drafts, typescript, typescript carbon, and proof, corrected, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 272-274)
    - "Introduction." Civil Service Poetry, printed version, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 275)
    - "Introduction." Poetry From Beowulf to the End of the Nineteenth Century, printed versions, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 276)
      Catalogue from Bertram Rota Ltd. at the Bookshop of Frank Hollings
    - "Introduction." Tree, Irish, The Marsh Picnic, draft, typescript, corrected, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 277)
    - "Introduction." Casson, Hugh Maxwell. Sketch Book: A Personal Choice of London Buildings, Drawn 1971-1974, printed version, signed, 1975
    - "Preface." Little, John E., Thomas Hughes: 1822-1896, printed version, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 278)
    - "The See of Canterbury," draft, typescript, corrected, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 279)
      Film pitch; includes letter from Betjeman to Peter Mills
    - Sir John Piers, draft, holograph, corrected, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 280)
    - Translation. Gerani by Filippo Donini, printed version, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 281)
    - Untitled, notes for address at memorial service for Noël Coward, draft, holograph, corrected, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 282)
    - Incomplete excerpts, printed versions, 1945-1950 (Box 4, Folder 283)
      Includes "Leaves in London" and "Satires and Suburbs" by Alan Ross
    - Photocopies of poetry manuscripts, undated (Box 4, Folder 284)
  - Notebooks
    - Notebook with title "J. Betjeman Churches Seen in Rome October 1936" (Box 4, Folder 285)
      Includes essay "The Harm of Antiquarianism" and numerous drawings
    - Notebook with working drafts of poems (such as "A Lincolnshire Church"), notes about churches, sketches, and personal reflections, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 286)
    - Notebook with working drafts of poems (including a poem about Betjeman's teddy bear Archibald), notes about churches, and sketches, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 287)
  - Publicity
    - Publisher's Announcements, circa 1940-1983 (Box 4, Folder 288)
  - Writings of Others
    - "Betjemania," programs, posters, publicity material and other correspondence, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 289)
      Musical comedy entertainment based on the works of John Betjeman
    - Brooke, Jocelyn. Ronald Firbank and John Betjeman. London: Published for the British Council and the National Book League by Longmans, Green & Co., 1962 (Box 4, Folder 290)
      Writers and their Work No. 153
    - "A Catalogue of Works by Sir John Betjeman From the Collection of Ray Carter." London: Warren Editions, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 291)
    - Comper, J.N. "Of the Atmosphere of a Church." London: Sheldon Press, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 292)
      Inscribed by Betjeman and includes note from Betjeman to Mr. Bryson
    - Fermor, Patrick Leigh. "In Honour of Mr. John Betjeman." Cornhill Magazine, circa 1950 (Box 5, Folder 293)
    - Gawsworth, John. "Betjeman's Birthday: Other New Unpublished Pieces," holograph, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 294)
      Includes letter from Betjeman (1968 August 27)
    - ---. "Concerning John Betjeman: Some Memories," drafts, holograph and typescript, 1969 February 28 (Box 5, Folder 295-296)
    - Grigson, Geoffrey. "Hendren -- Rhododendron," holograph, undated (Box 5, Folder 297)
    - Heaven, J.W.G. "Marlborough College," printed version, signed by the author and inscribed from Betjeman to Beverley Nichols, undated (Box 5, Folder 298)
    - Murray, John. "A Poet and His Publisher," London: The English Association, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 299)
      Presidential Address
    - Petscheck, Willa. "The Betjeman Phenomenon," draft, typescript, corrected, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 300)
      Includes related correspondence
    - Plomer, William. "John Betjeman," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 301)
      Published in Contemporary Poets of the English Language. Chicago: St. James Press
    - Press, John. "John Betjeman." London: Published for the British Council by Longmans, Green & Co., 1974 (Box 5, Folder 302)
      Writers and the Work No. 237
    - Sewell, Brocard. Olive Custance: Her Life and Work. London: The Eighteen Nineties Society, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 303)
    - Sieveking, Lance. "John Betjeman and Dorset." Dorset: J. Stevens Cox, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 304)
    - Stanford, Derek. John Betjeman: A Study, author's notebooks, holograph and drafts, typescript, corrected; related correspondence; and original photographs and illustrations used in the publication, circa 1961 (Box 5, Folder 305-308)
    - ---. "The Poetry of John Betjeman," draft typescript and proof, corrected, circa 1958 (Box 5, Folder 309)
      Includes letter to Stanford from Betjeman (1958 February 11)
    - Walker, C.R. "The Religious Significance of T.S. Eliot," printed version, annotated by Betjeman, undated (Box 5, Folder 310)
    - Wilson, Robert. "A Bibliography of Works by Gregory Corso," printed version, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 311)
- Personal Papers, 1908-1989; Series III; 0.42; (1 box)
  The series is organized into two subseries: Photographs and Other Papers.
  Personal papers contains photographs of Betjeman as well as other personal items, such as sketchbooks, a diary, and other ephemera. The photographs are mostly candid snapshots, although the series includes some formal portraits of Betjeman. Family and friends are also captured in the photographs, which portray the Betjemans while in Ireland and in old age, as well as a playful shot from Osbert Lancaster's sixtieth birthday party.
  Betjeman's sketchbook and loose drawings capture various churches, homes, landscapes, and streetscapes, mostly in pen and ink. Betjeman drew people less frequently, although his sketches here include caricatures of George Alfred Kolkhorst, or "Colonel" Kolkhorst from Betjeman's Oxford days. Betjeman's diary for 1954 is a mix of professional and personal responsibilities, ranging from meetings and BBC recordings to notes about his children's comings and goings.
  - Photographs
    - John Betjeman as a child, circa 1908 (Box 6, Folder 312)
    - John Betjeman with friends and family, Ireland, circa 1941 (Box 6, Folder 313)
    - Informal portraits of John Betjeman and Penelope Chetwode, 1961-1975, undated (Box 6, Folder 314)
    - Betjeman and Chetwode at Osbert Lancaster's sixtieth birthday party, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 315)
  - Other Papers
    - Ten resolutions, holograph, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 316)
    - Sketchbook, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 317)